- What have you done to them?!
- They're no longer human beings, just fictional characters
- 你对他们做了什么？  - 他们不再是人类，而成虚构角色了
Now, if you consent to take my place here,
they can be released.
现在，如果你同意接替我这里的位置，就可以释放他们
- You really would do that?
- No, my dear sir. You would.
- 你真的会这么干？  - 不，亲爱的先生。你会
Once you take up your post here, it can be
your first official task as the new controller.
一旦你在这里就位，它就可以成为你担任管理员的第一项正式任务
- I see. How very ingenious.
- I take it, then, that you agree?
- 我明白了, 真是天才啊  - 这么说你是同意了？
No! My answer is still no!
不！我的答案仍然是不！
How very unfortunate.
真是非常不幸
I'm sorry to have to use violent methods,
but you must submit.
我很抱歉不得不使用暴力手段了, 你必须投降
You have no alternative.
你没有其它选择
I have yet to see a robot...that can climb!
我还要看看机器人...怎么往上爬！
You cannot escape...
你逃不了的
but we will play your game a little longer.
不过我们可以多玩一会儿你的游戏
(CHUCKLES)
(CREAKING)
- Doctor!  - Zoe! Jamie!
- 博士！  - Zoe! Jamie!
- Am I glad to see you.
- The Master said you'd been...
- 见到你真高兴  - 大师说你已经被...
- Where do we go from here?
- Back to the Tardis.
- 我们接下来往哪儿走？  -  回到 TARDIS 去
We can't do that. It fell apart.
You don't remember?
我们不能去了。它已经散架了，你们不记得了？
- It's all over now. Thank goodness.
- The Tardis broke up.
- 这下完了，感谢老天  - TARDIS 坏掉了
- Yes, you said that.
- I'm tired. I think I'll sit down and have a rest.
- 是的, 你已经说过了  - 我累了, 我觉得还是坐下来，歇一会儿
- Is something wrong, Zoe?
- Where do we go from here?
- 出什么问题了, Zoe?  - 我们接下来往哪儿走？
- Back to the Tardis.
- We can't do that. It broke up. You don't remember?
- 回到 TARDIS 去  - 我们不能去了, 它散架了，你们不记得了？
But you keep saying the same things.
但你们一直在说同样的事情
The Tardis broke up.
TARDIS 散架了
Then it's true. They're not real.
They've been turned into fiction.
那么这是真的了, 他们不是真人, 他们已经变成虚构的了了
What's this?
这是什么？
The master tape! I wonder...
主磁带！我在想...
Perhaps if I were to create a few
immortal words of fiction of my own...
也许如果我自己建立一些永恒的虚构作品...
Yes. It's worth trying.
是的, 这值得一试
Oh... What I need is the strength of Karkus!
噢...我需要的是 Karkus 的力量
- I am at your command.
- Oh, thank you, my dear sir.
- 我听候你的命令  - 哦, 谢谢你, 亲爱的先生
Perhaps you could release this for me.
也许你可以帮我打开这个
- Zis is what you want?
- No. I don’t actually want it.
- 这就是你想要的？  - 不, 我并不是想要它
- You see. I want to get down here somehow.
- Ah. Wait.
- 你看，不知怎地我想要下去这里  - 啊，等一下
Thank you.
谢谢你
Jamie...
Jamie...﻿
Jamie, Zoe...you are being controlled.
Jamie, Zoe...你们被控制了
Jamie, listen! Listen!
Jamie, 听着！听着！
- Oh, it's no use.  - A rope.
- 噢, 没有用  - 一根绳子
- Oh, thank you.  - Ouch! Careful.
- 噢, 谢谢你   - 嗷！小心点
Oh. Yes, of course.
You are the Princess Rapunzel.
哦, 是的, 当然了, 你是 Rapunzel 公主
- Are you a prince?  - No, I'm afraid not.
- 你是一位王子吗？  - 不, 恐怕不是
Would you mind if I used your hair?
你介意我借用一下你的头发吗？
No, of course not. Everybody else uses it.
I don’t see why you shouldn’t...
不, 当然不介意．每个人都用它。我看不出为什么不让你...
Thank you. Where can we attach the...?
Oh, yes, of course.
谢谢你．我们可以把它绑到...? 哦, 是的, 当然了
(MACHINES WHIRR)
(KEYS CLICK)
Yes, yes. Go on.
好啊好啊, 继续
''The enemy had been
finally defeated by the Doctor...''
"敌人最终被博士击退了...
No, no. I can't say that. If I say that...
不, 不, 我不能那么说．如果我那么说...
I nearly fell for it. Another two seconds
and I should have turned myself into fiction.
我就掉进去了．晚两秒我就把自己变成了虚构人物了
Now, we shall play games no longer.
现在，我们不再玩游戏了
- I'm very obliged to you both.
- Always happy to be of assistance.
- 我非常感激你们  - 能帮上忙总是很高兴
Jamie and Zoe. I left them here.
Where are they? Jamie! Zoe!
Jamie 和 Zoe, 我把他们留在这里的, 现在哪里去了？Jamie! Zoe!
(CHUCKLING)
''Jamie and Zoe realised at last
"Jamie 和 Zoe 最终发现...
''that the Doctor was, in fact,
the most monstrous and cunning villain.
"博士实际上是最可怕最狡猾的恶棍
''There was no punishment too severe
for the crimes that he had committed.''
"对他所犯下的罪行而言, 什么样的惩罚都不算严厉＂
(ROBOTS BEEPING)
Splendid. Splendid.
Come closer, my children.
很棒, 很棒！靠近点, 孩子们
You sent for us, Master?
你派人叫我们来, 大师？
Now you know what your friend,
the Doctor, is really like, don't you?
现在你们知道博士的真实面目了, 对吧？
He's a monstrous and cunning villain.
他是最可怕最狡猾的恶棍
No punishment is too severe for
his crimes he had committed.
就他所犯下的罪行, 什么样的惩罚都不算严厉
Word perfect. That is why I sent for
you both at this moment of crisis.
完美的描述．这就是为什么在此危机时刻我派人叫你俩来
- We need your help.
- Tell us what we must do?
- 我们需要你的帮助  - 告诉我们必须做什么？
Well...
这样...
♪ A-tishoo! A-tishoo!
♪ We all fall down! ♪
I understand, sir, that you are
in an unhappy situation.
我明白，你处于一个并不乐观的局面
- Is there anything we can do to help?
- I wish there was.
- 有什么我们可以帮忙的吗？  - 我期望有
- Look!  - What's that?
- 那是什么？
I never saw it before.
之前我从没见过
The Tardis!
是 TARDIS!
Safe and sound! By all that's wonderful!
完好无损！这是最棒的了！
- Doctor, are you ready?
- The time has come to leave.
- 博士，你准备好了吗？  - 到了离开的时候了
- How did you find the Tardis?
- We'll explain that later.
- 你怎么找到 TARDIS 的？  - 我们稍后再解释那个
- Come on. We must get away.
- Just as I was thinking that all was over.
- 快来，我们必须得走了  - 正如我所料想的, 这一切都结束了
- Oh, no.
- It's not over yet, Doctor.
- 噢, 不  - 还没有结束, 博士
Not yet.
还没有
Jamie! Zoe!
Jamie! Zoe!﻿
(LAUGHTER)
What's happening?
发生了什么？
The children obeyed perfectly.
孩子们完美地遵循了指令
Their mission is completed.
他们的任务完成了
Now perhaps we can get down to business.
现在也许我们该来谈点正经的了
As you refused to take over at the controls,
由于你拒绝接管控制权
we were forced to incorporate you
into the computer itself.
我们被迫把你集成到电脑中
- To what purpose?
- To bring planet Earth under our control.
- 为了什么？  - 为了把地球带入我们的掌控之中
- And its people?
- We have no wish to destroy them.
- 还有它上面的人？  - 我们无意毁灭他们
Merely adjust their minds
to suit our purpose.
只是要调节他们的意识, 以满足我们的目的
Sausages! Man would become
like a string of sausages.
香肠！人类会变成一串香肠
Man will simply vanish from the Earth
and reappear here.
人们只是会从地球上消失, 重新出现在这里
Leaving Earth undamaged and uninhabited
for you to take over.
留下地球完好无损也无人居住, 好让你们接管
- Precisely.
- If I co-operate.
- 正是  - 这是假设我合作的情况下
You have no alternative.
You are part of the master brain.
你没有选择．你是我们主大脑的一部分了
So the computer
feeds off my thoughts, does it?
所以电脑能导入我的思想了, 是吗？
Correct.
正确
Then it will create what I think.
那它就会创造出我所想的东西
Oh, no. No... You're now under control
of the master brain.
噢, 不, 不...你处于主大脑的控制之下
Are you so sure?
You couldn't control my mind before...
你如此确信吗？你之前无法控制我的意识...
and you certainly can't control it now!
现在当然也不能！
- Submit!  - No!
- 投降！  - 不！
You've given me equal power.
It's a battle of wits between you and me.
你已经给了我同等的能力, 现在就是你与我之间斗智斗勇了
Oh, no. No! No! Stop! Stop!
噢, 不, 不！不！停下！停下！
Jamie, Zoe... Can you hear me?
Think for yourselves. Don't be afraid.
Jamie, Zoe...你们能听到吗？想着你们自己, 不要害怕
You can open the book.
Go on, you can do it.
你们可以把书打开的，继续，你们可以的
Oh. Oh, dear.
噢，噢，天啊
This is against everything we ever worked for.
这有悖于我们一直努力争取的一切啊
- (HUMMING)
- Warning, warning.
警告，警告
Emergency action.
Emergency. Emergency.
紧急行动。紧急。紧急
Calling white robots.
呼叫白色机器人
Guards will enter the control centre.
警卫要进入控制中心
The master brain must be protected.
主大脑必须得到保护
Push, Zoe. Push hard.
推，Zoe。使劲推
We will get out.
我们快出去了
- Soldiers! To the roof! Immediately!
- Harder. Harder!
- 士兵们！到房顶去！立刻！  - 用力，用力！
Splendid!
太棒了！
Soldiers, forward!
Seize them! Destroy them!
士兵们，前进！抓住他们！消灭他们！
- (CREAKING)  - Get back, Zoe.
回来，Zoe
(CREAKING)
Can't you help us?
你能帮我们吗？
We obey our creator. That is all
that can be expected of any character.
我们听命于我们的创造者, 所有角色预期都是这个行为模式
And now, Doctor, obey me!
现在，博士，服从我！
No!
不！
Suddenly the Karkus came to their rescue.
突然 Karkus 来救他们了
I am at your command.
我任你差遣
(DOCTOR) He raised his anti-molecular
disintegrator gun and destroyed the soldiers.
他举起他的反分子分解枪，消灭了这些士兵
No! But the Karkus realised his mistake
不！但 Karkus 意识到了自己的错误
and turned back to face his real enemies,
Jamie and Zoe!
转而面对他真正的敌人：Jamie 和 Zoe！
With Jamie and Zoe fixed firmly in his sights,
the Karkus pressed the trigger of his gun.
Karkus 紧紧地瞄准 Jamie 和 Zoe，扣下了扳机
But... But all the power had been used up
on the soldiers and it was useless.
但是...但是能量已经在士兵身上用光了，枪失去作用了
- You'll have to do better than that.
- Suddenly, a swashbuckling figure appeared.
- 你必须比我编得更好了  - 突然，一个强大的人物出现了
(Cyrano de Bergerac 本是十七世纪剑客/诗人/作家
(但更为人知的是同名戏剧中的主人公，该戏剧里添加了一些虚构情节)
Poet and swordsman,
the famous Cyrano de Bergerac.
诗人兼剑客, 著名的Cyrano de Bergerac
Remorselessly, Cyrano advanced on those
who had dared to poke fun at his nose.
Cyrano 冷酷无情地向那些想戳他鼻子的人发起了攻击
But wait.
但是等等
He found himself face to face
with the fearless musketeer
他发现与他面对面的是无畏的火枪手
and fearless swordsman D'Artagnan!
无畏的剑客达达里昂！
(大仲马《三个火枪手》主人公之一)
Come on, Zoe.
快点, Zoe
- Princess Rapunzel, can we borrow your hair again?
- Of course.
- Rapunzel 公主, 能再借用一下你的头发吗？  - 当然
- Why we going down there?
- We've got to find the Doctor. Come on.
- 我们为什么要下去？  - 我们得找到博士, 快点
Stop them! Substitute cutlass for rapier.
Cancel Cyrano.
阻止他们！把长剑换成弯刀, 取消 Cyrano
Blackbeard the Pirate!
黑胡子海盗！
(DOCTOR) Cancel D'Artagnan.
Substitute Sir Lancelot in full armour!
取消达达里昂．换上全副武装的兰斯洛特爵士
(兰斯洛特爵士: 亚瑟王圆桌骑士团成员之一, 也是其中最伟大最勇敢的骑士)
This way.
这边
(MASTER IN FLAT VOICE)
The Doctor is expendable, expendable.
博士是可以牺牲的，可以牺牲
He will be destroyed.
他将会被消灭
(NORMAL VOICE) Oh, no, no.
He's the only person. There's nobody else.
噢, 不, 不．他是唯一的人选, 没有其他人了
I can't go on for ever.
我不能永远持续下去
Please give me another chance.
请再给我一次机会
(FLAT VOICE) You have failed. The master brain
must be protected against overloading.
你已经失败了。主大脑必须得到保护, 防止超载
Robot force will deal with him.
将由机器人队伍来对付他
Change robot weapon to destructor beam.
将机器人的武器换为毁灭激光
(LOW BUZZ)
It is a pity that we have to destroy
such an intelligent mind as yours, Doctor,
很可惜，我们不得不摧毁你这么聪明的大脑,博士
but you leave us no alternative.
但你让我们没有退路了
Disintegrate!
分解！
(HUMMING)
Stop them!
阻止他们！
They will overload the master brain!
他们会主大脑超载的！
Destroy them. Destroy.
消灭他们, 消灭
Oh!
噢！
Zoe, duck!
Zoe, 蹲下！
(GUNFIRE AND EXPLOSIONS)
- Shouldn't we get out of here?
- Yes. Come on, Jamie, give me a hand.
- 我们该逃出这里吧？  - 是的。快来，Jamie, 帮我一下
- What do you want to bring him for?
- Don't argue, Jamie. Give a hand.
- 你想带他去做什么？  - 别吵了, Jamie，帮我一把
(EXPLOSIONS)
Why we had to bring him.
He is one of those caused the trouble.
我们为什么必须带上他, 他是造成这些问题的根源之一
- Are you all right, sir?
- I'm not sure where I am.
- 你还好吗, 先生？  - 我不清楚我在那里
Is this the office of the ''Ensign'' magazine?
这里是《上尉》杂志的编辑部吗？
You were kidnapped, just like we were.
They've been using your mind.
你被绑架了, 跟我们一样。他们一直在利用你的大脑
- What happens to us now?
- That depends on how efficient the white robots are.
- 我们现在会怎样？  - 这取决于那些白色机器人效率怎样
The last order was to destroy.
Let's hope they're destroying one another.
最后的指令是要消灭．我们就指望它们会互相消灭吧
What about the Karkus and Gulliver
and our other friends out there?
Karkus, 格列弗会怎样，还有我们的其他朋友们呢？
- You can't blow up a fictional character.
- But what about us?
- 你没法炸死一个虚构人物  - 但我们怎么办？
We'll have to hope the destruction
of the computer returns us all to reality.
我们只能期望电脑的毁灭会把我们崩回现实
- And you, my dear sir.
- Oh. Do you mean I'm going home?
- 你也是，亲爱的先生  - 噢, 你是说我可以回家了？
- I hope so.
- But it could just as well send us into oblivion.
- 我期望如此  - 但它也可能把我们送入湮灭
- You mean we could vanish for ever?
- We shall soon know.
- 你是说我们有可能永远消失？  - 很快我们就知道了
- (EXPLOSIONS)
- Hang on. Here it comes.
- 稳住, 它来了